♪Don't feel sad for the fallen flowers♪
♪ لا تشعر بالحزن على الزهور الحزينة ♪
♪Falling in the mortal world♪
♪ يتظاهر في العالم الفاني ♪
♪Keep all the memories♪
♪ استمر في جميع الذكريات ♪
♪Can't find any peace anymore♪
♪ لا يمكن العثور على أي سلام بعد الآن ♪
♪The storms can't kill my passion♪
♪ العواصف لا يمكن أن تقتل حمايتي ♪
♪But I need to endure♪
♪ لكنني بحاجة إلى تحمل ♪
♪Be serious even though I'm naive♪
♪ كن جادا على الرغم من أنني ساذجة ♪
♪If this is the destined fate♪
♪ إذا كان هذا هو القدر المقدر ♪
♪Even if I'll be hurt♪
حتى ولو تأذيت ♪
♪I'll protect the people♪
♪ سأحمي الناس ♪
♪The mountains sun and moon can be my witnesses♪
♪ الجبال الشمس والقمر يمكن أن يكون شاهداي ♪
♪Full of passion♪
♪ مليء بالحماقة ♪
♪Deep love and hatred♪
♪ الحب والكراهية العميق ♪
♪Melts in my heart along with the snow♪
♪ يذوب في قلبي مع الثلج ♪
=Royal Rumours=
= الشائعات الملكية =
=Episode 16=
= الحلقة 16 =
Don't tell me she won't come.
لا تخبرني أنها لن تأتي
Probably not.
على الأرجح لا
No way.
لا يمكن
I don't believe it.
لا أصدق ذلك
She will come.
ستأتي
Who said I won't come?
من قال إنني لن آتي؟
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
Be careful.
كن حذرا
I finally see you.
أراك أخيرا
I've been waiting at your house all day today,
كنت أنتظر منزلك طوال اليوم
but you didn't show up.
لكنك لم تأت
Liuli.
ليولي
- What are they doing up there? - This is tiring.
- ماذا يفعلون هناك؟ - هذا مُرهق - هذا متعب
Why don't you ask?
لماذا لا تسألين؟
She is a short temper.
إنها مزاجية قصيرة
I'll give you half my pay.
سأعطيك نصف أجري
You go and ask.
اذهب وأسأل
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
Do you know what His Highness
هل تعرف ما يتحدث عنه سموه
and Princess Hua are talking about?
والأميرة هوا تتحدث؟
What are they talking about?
عمّ يتحدثون؟
It's none of your business.
هذا ليس من شأنك
You just wrote, "back of the hill".
كتبت للتو، "ظهر التل"
You could drive our horse to death.
يمكنك دفع حصاننا حتى الموت
It is
القمر
a full moon today.
القمر مليء اليوم
Yes. There are a lot of stars, too.
نعم، هناك الكثير من النجوم أيضا
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
Did you have a drink with my father?
هل احتسيت مشروبا مع والدي؟
Yes.
نعم
General Hua's liquor tolerance is truly amazing.
خمور الجنرال هوا التسامح مذهل حقا
I almost passed out.
كدت تفقد الوعي
I was told that
قيل لي
you were too tired
كنت متعبًا جدًا
and went straight to your room.
وذهبا إلى غرفتك مباشرةً
So I didn't want to bother you.
لذلك لم أشأ إزعاجك
Yes.
نعم
The envoys
المبعوثون
were arriving one after another.
كانوا يصلون واحدا تلو الآخر
After I settled them
بعد أن قمت بتوطينهم
into Longjing House,
إلى دار لونغجينغ
I entertained them.
لقد فكرت بهم
It was a bit tough.
كان الأمر صعبا بعض الشيء
Then I'll get you some men tomorrow.
إذًا سأحضر لك بعض الرجال غدًا
You are the Ceremonial Officer.
أنت موظفة المراسم
You don't have to do everything personally.
ليس عليك فعل كل شيء كل شيء شخصيا
Did you come to my house today
هل أتيت إلى منزلي اليوم
to catch up with my family?
للحاق بعائلة؟
Yes.
نعم
I just wanted to visit
أردت فقط أن أزور
your family.
عائلتك
But when our family
ولكن عندما غادرت عائلتنا
moved away from the capital,
الابتعاد عن العاصمة
you were
كنت
just a child.
مجرد طفل
That's right.
هذا صحيح
Did my family treat you well?
هل عاملتك عائلتي بشكل جيد؟
Of course.
بالطبع
They were very kind to me.
كانوا طيبين جدًا معي
That's a relief.
هذا مريح
By the way,
بالمناسبة
this is
هذا هو
the haw balls my brother
كرات القعقاع أخي
got for me.
اذهب لي
It's delicious.
إنه لذيذ
Try it.
جربيه
Take this, too.
خذي هذا أيضًا
Is it good?
هل هي لذيذة؟
Yes.
نعم
By the way,
بالمناسبة
I've given you some jewellery today.
أعطيتك بعض المجوهرات اليوم
If General Wei doesn't like it,
إذا كان الجنرال وي لا يعجبه
remember to take it back.
تذكري أن استعده
Are they for me?
هل هي لي؟
Of course.
بالطبع
Actually,
في الحقيقة
I'd like to thank you
أود أن أشكرك
for the butterfly you made for me.
على الفراشة التي أعددتها لي
I slept at night
نمت في الليل
and dreamed of my mother.
وحلمت بأمي
Really?
حقا؟
She said
قالت
it wasn't because of the incense I offered,
لم يكن بسبب البخور الذي قدمته
but because a butterfly
ولكن بسبب الفراشة
came to her.
جاءت إليها
So you went to
لذلك ذهبت
honour your mother that day.
احترام والدتك في ذلك اليوم
Actually,
في الحقيقة
I am envious
أنا أحسد
of your family.
من عائلتك
His Highness's mother.
والدة سموه
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
My family and I
أنا وعائلتي
will take good care of
سوف أعتني جيدا
His Highness.
سموه
Why do you think
لماذا ترى
I was so happy
كنت سعيدة جدا
when His Highness said he actually
في الحقيقة
paid respects to his mother?
قدم الاحترام لوالدته؟
Happy.
سعيدة
Besides,
بالإضافة إلى ذلك
he asked me to go to the back of the hill at this hour.
طلب مني أن أذهب إلى الخلف في هذه الساعة
Not only did I go,
لم أذهب فحسب
I was so happy.
كنت سعيدة جدًا
Happy.
سعيدة
Do you think
هل تعتقد
I have
لدي
a feeling for His Highness?
شعور لسموه؟
Two buns and one deep-fried dough stick.
كعك وعصا الضباب المقلي العميق
Are you even
هل يمكنكم
listening to me?
الاستماع إليّ؟
Miss.
الآنسة
You've repeated it 50 times.
كررته 50 مرة
Please let me go.
أرجوك دعني أذهب
You can talk to your brother
يمكنك التحدث إلى أخيك
or Uncle Song.
أو عمي سونغ
Just let me go, please.
فقط دعني أذهب، من فضلك
Miss.
الآنسة
Young Master Yun, you are awake.
السيد يون، أنت مستيقظ
Slowly.
ببطء
Let me help you.
دعني أساعدك
Don't say a word.
لا تقل كلمة
Drink the medicine first.
اشربي الدواء أولًا
Here.
تفضلي
Sorry, it's hot.
آسفة، إنه ساخن
I...
أنا...
It's okay.
لا بأس
I'm fine.
أنا بخير
Here.
هنا
I'm sorry, Young Master Yun.
آسف، السيد يون
I didn't mean it.
لم أكن أقصد ذلك
I...
أنا...
I'll drink it myself.
سأشربه بنفسي
I have always thought
لقد كنت أفكر دائما
you were
كنت
a weak girl who only stayed in your room,
فتاة ضعيفة بقيت في غرفتك فقط
but now I realised that
لكنني أدركت الآن أنك
you are
أنت
a virtuous lady.
سيدة فاضلة
I misjudged you.
لقد أخطأت في حقك
A lady is all about manners and a gentleman is all about righteousness.
السيدة معنية بالأخلاق الرجل النبيل هو كل شيء عن البر
There is no conflict between the two.
لا صراع بين الاثنين
Don't take it to heart.
لا تأخذ الأمر على محمل الجد
After all, we all can get it wrong
بعد كل شيء، يمكننا جميعا أن نفهم الأمر
at the first time.
في المرة الأولى
Then
إذن
what do you think of me?
ما رأيك بي؟
You may be
قد تكون
doing something dangerous,
القيام بشيء خطير
but I can tell from your music
ولكن يمكنني أن أقول من موسيقاتك
that you have a great sense
أن لديك حسا رائعا
of righteousness.
من البر
What is this?
ما هذا؟
Please give this jade whistle
يرجى إعطاء هذا بياض اليشم
to Princess Hua
إلى الأميرة هوا
and ask her
وأطلب منها
to pass it to His Highness.
لتمر عبر سموه
Do you want Princess Hua to pass it to His Highness?
هل تريد الأميرة هوا لتمر بها إلى سموه؟
I don't think this is appropriate.
لا أعتقد أن هذا مناسب
Rest assured.
اطمئن
You can do it.
يمكنك القيام بذلك
I'll explain it to you
سأشرحه لك
when you have completed this task.
عندما تنتهي من هذه المهمة
Young Master Yun bore the disgrace
تحمل السيد يون العار
and was lurking around the Crown Prince
وكان كامنا حول ولي عهد
to seek revenge against the State of Jin.
لالتماس الانتقام من ولاية جين
Jinpo has always
كانت جينبو دائما
been at odds with the State of Jin.
كانت في خلاف مع دولة جين
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
عدو عدوي هو صديقي
I certainly intend to make friends with him.
أعتزم بالتأكيد تكوين صداقات معه
What do you think of her?
ما رأيك بها؟
She's good.
إنها جيدة
There are just a bunch of
هناك مجرد حفنة من الموسيقيين
bored musicians at Jinling Garden.
موسيقيون محترفون في حديقة جينلينغ
It's not a classy place at all.
هذا ليس مكانًا راقيًا على الإطلاق
This place is more interesting.
هذا المكان أكثر إثارة للاهتمام
Yun Han
يون هان
is indeed one of our own.
هو بالفعل واحد منا
According to you,
ووفقا لك
he did not agree to cooperate.
لم يوافق على التعاون
(Qing Yue?)
(تشينغ يويه؟)
Yes.
نعم
Since he refused,
بما أنه رفض
I have to kill him.
يجب أن أقتله
Since he's a rebel,
نظرا لأنه متمرد
he can be eliminated.
يمكن القضاء عليه
However,
لكن
he must have escaped.
لا بد أنه هرب
Master.
معلمي
If Yun Han appears,
إذا ظهر يون هان
I will inform you
سوف أبلغك
to kill him.
لقتله
This place has been discovered.
تم اكتشاف هذا المكان
You must have been followed.
لا بد أنه قد تم متابعتك
I need to move again.
أحتاج إلى التحرك مرة أخرى
Now
الآن
you can't go back to Jinling Garden either.
لا يمكنك العودة حديقة جينلينغ أيضا
Why don't you move with us?
لماذا لا تتحركين معنا؟
(Ankang Garden)
(حديقة أنكانغ)
Qing Yue is Yun Han's attendant.
تشينغ يويه هو بطل يون هان
He's the one who sold Yun Han out.
إنه الشخص الذي بيع يون هان
And behind Qing Yue
وخلف تشينغ يويه
may well be
قد يكون
the person you've been looking for.
الشخص الذي كنت تبحث عنه
He Yuanting
خه
seems to be trying to find this person
يبدو أنها تحاول العثور على هذا الشخص
through Yun Han.
عن طريق يون هان
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
It all
كل منها
ties together.
يربط بينهما
I'm afraid
أنا خائف أنه
that Yun Han deliberately
أن يون هان
gave the wrong information
قدم معلومات خاطئة عن قصد
because we've been watching Princess Hua.
لأننا كنا مراقبة الأميرة هوا
Your Highness.
سموك
You need to make
عليك أن تتخذ
a real decision now.
قرار حقيقي الآن
Kill that Qing Yue.
اقتلوا ذلك تشينغ يويه
Take everything out
خذ كل شيء
of his room.
كل شيء
The best way to protect Yun Han
أفضل طريقة لحماية يون هان
is to make him disappear without a trace.
هو لجعله يختفي من دون أثر
This...
هذا...
Since Yun Han
منذ يون هان
Since Yun Han didn't work with He Yuanting,
بما أن يون هان لم يعمل مع خه يوانتينغ
he's still my man.
إنه لا يزال لي
I can ignore
يمكنني تجاهل
all his previous mistakes.
كل أخطائه السابقة
He has to come back alive.
عليه أن يعود حيًا
Then
إذن
was it Yun Han who had eliminated
هل كان يون هان الذي قضى على
all the undercover spies?
جميع الجواسيس السرية؟
Yes.
نعم
But...
لكن
That's too cruel.
هذا قاس جدًا
Have you ever thought
هل فكرت أبدا
that this is actually Yun Han's
أن هذا هو
plea for help in disguise?
طلب المساعدة في شكل مقنع؟
When Princess Hua was kidnapped,
عندما اختطفت الأميرة هوا
dispatching all the black-armored army
إرسال كل الجيش الأسود العاري
would certainly alert the Imperial Court,
من شأنه أن ينذر بالتأكيد المحكمة الإمبراطورية
but even if the spies were discovered,
ولكن حتى لو تم اكتشاف الجواسيس
it would be impossible to eliminate them all.
سيكون من المستحيل للقضاء عليها جميعا
I guess
أعتقد
Yun Han was trying to hoodwink the other side with this,
كان يون هان يحاول غش الجانب الآخر بهذا
which could lead to
يمكن أن يؤدي إلى
a very suspicious point
نقطة مشبوهة للغاية
and hoped we'd look into it.
ونأمل أن ننظر في الأمر
But probing will lead
لكن البحث سوف يؤدي
to death, Your Highness.
حتى الموت يا صاحب السمو
Maybe
ربما
he's testing my sincerity.
إنه يختبر إخلاصي
Life and death
الحياة والموت
are at my fingertips.
لست في متناول يدي
Go now.
اذهبي الآن
Yes.
نعم
Be safe.
كوني آمنة
(Yun Han.)
(يون هان)
(You have shed blood for me)
(لقد سفكت الدماء لي)
(all these years.)
(كل هذه السنوات)
(I have faith in you.)
(أنا أثق بك)
(So don't fail me.)
(لذلك لا تخذلك)
(Hua Mansion)
(طائفة هوا)
Du.
دو
Liuli.
ليولي
Are you here to see me?
هل أنت هنا لرؤيتي؟
May I have a word?
هل لي بكلمة؟
Wait here.
انتظر هنا
Come here.
تعالي إلى هنا
I came in haste,
جئت على عجل
unprepared
غير مستعد
and unannounced.
وغير مُعلن عنه
Please forgive my rudeness.
أرجوكم سامحوا وقاحتي
It's fine.
إنه جيد
You can come to me
يمكنك أن تأتي إليّ
anytime you want.
في أي وقت تريد
I'm glad to see you.
أنا سعيد لرؤيتك
Why do you want to see me?
لماذا تريدين رؤيتي؟
I...
أنا...
Please pass this
يرجى المرور بهذا
to His Highness.
إلى سموه
His Highness?
سمو؟
Why don't you give it
لماذا لا تعطيه
to him yourself?
له بنفسك؟
No, Liuli.
لا يا ليولي
Don't get me wrong.
لا تسئ فهمي
I...
أنا...
This is not
هذا ليس
a token of love or something.
رمز الحب أو ما شابه
Trust me.
ثق بي
A token of love?
رمز الحب؟
No.
لا
This...
هذا...
This is really not a token of love.
هذا حقًا ليس أمارة حب
I...
أنا...
How should I explain it?
كيف أشرح الأمر؟
Anyway,
على أية حال
I didn't ask you
لم أطلب منكم
to bring this to His Highness
لإحضاره هذا
just because I like him.
فقط لأنني أحبه
Just help me
ساعدني فقط
pass this to him.
مررها إليه
Xiuying.
شي يينغ
I'm getting more confused.
إنني أشعر بمزيد من الارتباك
What exactly is
من هو بالضبط
a token of love?
هدية الحب؟
If a man and a woman
إذا كان الرجل والمرأة
are deeply in love,
في حب عميق
they give each other a token,
أن يعطوا بعضهم البعض رمز
it means
وهذا يعني
they like each other.
أن يعجبا ببعضهما البعض
I always give His Highness
أعطي سموه دائما
snacks.
الوجبات الخفيفة
Is that also a token of love?
هل هذا أيضا رمز للحب؟
If you think it is,
إذا كنت تعتقد أنه كذلك
then yes.
إذن نعم
(Ankang Garden)
(حديقة آنكانغ)
(If a man and a woman)
(إذا كان رجلا وامرأة)
(are deeply in love,)
(في حب عميق،)
(they give each other a token,)
(يعطيان بعضهما البعض رمز،)
(it means they like each other.)
(هذا يعني أنهما يحبان بعضهما البعض)
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Nothing.
لا شيء
I...
أنا...
Well,
إذن
Xiuying asked me to pass you this.
طلب مني شي يينغ أن أمر لك هذا
(This is Yun Han's jade whistle.)
(هذا هو بياض اليشم لدى يون هان)
(Why was it with Lady Du?)
(لماذا كانت مع السيدة دو؟)
(Could it be...)
(هل يمكن أن يكون...)
Miss.
الآنسة
Did His Highness
هل تنمر سموه
bully you?
يتنمر عليك؟
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
I think...
أعتقد...
I think I like His Highness.
أعتقد أنني أحب سموه
Miss.
الآنسة
Let me ask you a question.
دعني أسألك سؤالا
Sure.
بالطبع
Do you like me?
هل أنت مُعجب بي؟
Yes.
نعم
Do you like your brother?
هل أعجبك أخوك؟
You like so many people.
أنت تحب الكثير من الناس
What's so special about
ما مميزة بالنسبة لك
you being fond of His Highness?
أن تحبني من سموه؟
At best, you just
في أفضل الأحوال، أنت فقط
turn an enemy into a friend.
إلى صديق
But...
لكن...
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Of course.
بالطبع
Let's go back.
دعنا نعد
Put your outfit back on.
ضع قميصك الرياضي مرة أخرى
I'm sorry.
أنا آسفة
It was rude of me.
كنت وقحة
Hurry up.
بسرعة
Are you done?
هل انتهيت؟
Yes.
نعم
Forgive me for my rudeness.
سامحني على وقاحتي
I have
لقد
delivered the jade whistle
سلم هزيلة اليشم
to Princess Hua for you.
إلى الأميرة هوا من أجلك
Princess Hua is a kind lady.
الأميرة هوا سيدة طيبة
She will definitely help you
سوف تساعدك بالتأكيد
pass it to His Highness.
مررها إلى سموه
Thank you, Lady Du.
شكرا لك، السيدة دو
I don't know if
لا أعرف
I've interrupted your life
لقد قاطعت حياتك
in the last few days.
في الأيام القليلة الماضية
Indeed.
بالفعل
However,
لكن
I don't usually go out either.
أنا أيضًا لا أخرج عادة
My grandfather has recently caught a cold
جدتي قد أصيب مؤخرا بنزلة برد
and is unwell.
ولا بأس
So most of the servants
لذلك معظم الخدم
are taking care of him.
يعتنون به
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
Once I've recovered,
بمجرد أن أتعافى
I'll leave here
سأغادر هنا
as soon as I can.
في أقرب وقت ممكن
I...
أنا...
I didn't mean to drive you away.
لم أقصد طردك بعيدا
I get it.
فهمت فحسب
Thank you
شكرًا لك
for saving my life this time.
لإنقاذ حياتي هذه المرة
Actually,
في الحقيقة
His Highness and I...
أنا وصاحب السمو
No need to explain.
لا حاجة للشرح
Since it's your secret,
بما أنه سرا لك
you don't have to tell me.
ليس عليك أن تخبرني
I...
أنا...
I'll go and boil the herbs.
سأذهب لتناول الأعشاب
Take a good rest.
خذ قسطا جيدا من الراحة
(Qunying Eatery)
(إتيري تشينغ)
Prince Ying.
الأمير ينغ
We have a lot of customers today.
لدينا الكثير من الزبائن اليوم
This business is booming.
هذا العمل يزدهر
Maybe today
ربما اليوم
we can turn a loss into a profit.
يمكننا أن نحول الخسارة إلى ربح
Did Princess Jiamin come today?
هل جاءت الأميرة جيامين اليوم؟
No, she didn't.
لا لم تفعل
(Qunying Eatery)
(إتيري Qunينغ)
Prince Ying.
الأمير ينغ
You must remember
يجب أن تتذكر
why you ran for the post of
لماذا ترشحت لمنصب
Ceremonial Officer.
موظفة مراسم
If you give in now,
إذا أعطيتني الآن
that means you are
هذا يعني أنك
surrendering everything.
استسلم كل شيء
Prince Ying.
الأمير ينغ
Let's open a shop.
دعنا نفتح متجر
Sure.
بالطبع
What do you think
ما رأيك
of the name?
من الاسم؟
(Qunying Eatery)
(تشينغ إيتري)
Yangcao Eatery?
يانغكاو إيتري؟
It's a grand name.
إنه اسم ضخم
It is brilliant and perfect.
إنه رائع ومثالي
Princess Jiamin.
الأميرة جيامين
It is called Qunying Eatery.
يطلق عليها إثم تشينينغ
Greetings, Prince Ying.
تحياتي، الأمير ينغ
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
Have you seen Princess Jiamin recently?
هل رأيت الأميرة جيامين مؤخرا؟
I did see her
لقد رأيتها
recently,
مؤخرا
but she didn't
لكنها لم تظهر
seem happy.
تبدو سعيدة
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
I know you have always admired me,
أعلم أنك دائما معجبة بي
but
ولكن
I may not be able to accept it.
قد لا أكون قادرا على قبوله
Before, I thought that
من قبل، كنت أعتقد
if father granted me a marriage,
إذا منح لي الأب زواجا
I would just accept it,
أود فقط أن أقبل ذلك
but now
ولكن الآن
I seem to have
يبدو أن لدي
second thoughts.
الأفكار الثانية
So you should
لذلك يجب عليك
keep this.
حافظ على هذه
Although this doll
على الرغم من هذه الدمية
looks a bit like me,
تبدو مثلي قليلًا
which shows how much you like me,
مما يظهر مدى إعجابك بي
but
لكن
I will have to let you down.
سأخذلك
Prince Ying.
الأمير ينغ
I never said
لم أقل
this doll is for you.
هذه الدمية لك
I just heard that
سمعت فقط أن
Jiamin
جيامين
fancies this little thing.
يؤلمني هذا الشيء الصغير
So Jiamin likes this.
لذا يحب جيامين هذا
What does it have to do with me?
ما علاقة هذا بي؟
Since she likes it,
بما أنها تحبها
you should give it to her.
يجب أن تعطيها إياه
Even I get it.
حتى أنني فهمت
Do we have to make it so clear?
هل علينا أن نبين ذلك بوضوح؟
Thank you, Princess Hua.
شكرا لك يا أميرة هوا
Prince Ying.
الأمير ينغ
Don't be so courteous.
لا تكوني مهذبة جدا
We owe you a big thank you
نحن مدينون لك بالشكر الكبير
for supporting our business.
لدعم أعمالنا
Also,
وأيضا
it's our pleasure
يسرنا
that you like our pottery dolls
أنك تحبين دمية الفخار لدينا
so much.
إلى هذه الدرجة
Just say you got it for her,
قلت فقط إنك حصلت عليها لها
not our Princess.
وليس أميرتنا
Why?
لماذا؟
Just do it.
فقط افعل ذلك
Thank you, Princess Hua.
شكرا لك يا أميرة هوا
That's how you use a love token.
هكذا تستخدم هدية الحب
Princess, eat something.
الأميرة، تناولي شيئا
(Serenity)
"الصفاء"
I have no appetite.
لا شهية لديّ
Princess.
الأميرة
Are you sure
هل أنت متأكد
you don't want to meet Prince Ying?
ألا تريد مقابلة الأمير ينغ؟
What's the point?
ما الفائدة؟
He does nothing
إنه لا شيء
but to piss me off.
إلا أن أشفق علي
I was told that Prince Ying
قيل لي إن الأمير ينغ
was standing outside for a long time.
كان يقف في الخارج لفترة طويلة
Then tell him I'm busy
إذن أخبره أنني مشغول
and ask him to leave.
وأطلب منه المغادرة
Yes.
نعم
(Grand Preceptor Mansion)
(قصر المعلم الكبير)
(It's His Highness.)
(إنه الأمير)
(Looks like he got the jade whistle.)
(يبدو أنه حصل على نزهة اليشم)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Please rise.
انهض
You don't really
أنت حقا
have to come here yourself.
يجب أن تأتي إلى هنا بنفسك
No.
لا
As I said before,
كما قلت من قبل
wherever you go,
أينما ذهبت
I will try to find you.
سأحاول العثور عليك
I must keep
يجب أن أفي
my promise.
وعدي
Young Master Yun.
سيد الشباب يون
(He left without saying goodbye.)
(غادر دون الوداع)
(I will make up for your dowry.)
(سأعوض مهرك)
Looks like you've met the right person.
يبدو أنك قابلت الشخص الصحيح
When you were in danger,
عندما كنت في خطر
this person gave you ginseng soup
أعطاك هذا الشخص حساء الجنسنغ
and treated the wound in time.
ومعالجة الجرح في الوقت المناسب
Otherwise,
خلاف ذلك
you would have contracted a disease.
كنت ستصاب بمرض
Your Highness.
سموك
He is now recovering
إنه يتعافى الآن
and just needs to recuperate.
ويحتاج فقط إلى التعافي
I have given him
لقد قدمت له
some prescriptions to nourish his body.
بعض الوصفات الطبية للتغذية جسده
Qi, Ba.
تشي، با
See Physician Qiu off.
انظر الطبيب تشيو بعيدا
- Yes.
- نعم
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو
This way, Physician Qiu.
بهذه الطريقة، الطبيب تشيو
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Lady Du saved me.
السيدة دو أنقذتني
Why was it
لماذا كانت
Lady Du who saved you?
السيدة دو من أنقذتك؟
I was lucky
كان محظوظًا
to run into her by chance.
لمصادفتها عن طريق الصدفة
The information I received that day was false.
المعلومات التي تلقيتها في ذلك اليوم كانت مزيفة في ذلك اليوم
The second prince of Jinpo
الأمير الثاني من جينبو
is currently in the capital.
حاليا في العاصمة
Why?
لماذا؟
Have you already known?
هل كنت تعرف بالفعل؟
Since He Yuanting
بما أنه يوانتينغ
is already in the capital,
بالفعل في العاصمة
I'll keep an eye on him as planned.
سأراقبه كما هو مخطط له
You did very well.
أبليت بلاء حسنًا
Take a good rest.
خذي قسطا جيدا من الراحة
(Minister Mansion)
(حفل الوزير)
Princess.
الأميرة
Why aren't we going in?
لماذا لا نذهب؟
We'll go in
سنذهب
when Prince Ying has left.
عندما غادر الأمير ينغ
What if he won't leave?
ماذا إذا لم يغادر؟
He waited outside
انتظر في الخارج
all day last time.
طوال اليوم المرة الماضية
Your parents
والداك
came out to greet him in person.
خرج لتحضيره شخصيا
Since you refused to see him,
بما أنك رفضت رؤيته
your mother persuaded him to leave.
أقنعته أمك بالمغادرة
I didn't expect him to come again today.
لم أكن أتوقع منه أن يأتي مرة أخرى اليوم
He told me
قال لي
that he had been very stubborn since young.
أنه كان عنيد جدًا منذ صغره
He probably won't leave
غالبًا لن يغادر
until he sees me.
حتى يراني
Come here.
تعالي إلى هنا
Listen.
استمع
We can't go that way.
لا يمكننا فعل ذلك
We have to climb up.
علينا أن نتسلق
What?
ماذا؟
Just do it.
افعلي ذلك فحسب
Come on, help me.
هيا، ساعدني
Be careful.
توخ الحذر
It's a little high.
هذا مرتفع بعض الشيء
Hong.
هونغ
Hong, hold me.
هونغ، أمسكي بي
Don't worry. I'm here.
لا تقلق، أنا هنا
Be careful.
انتبهوا
I'm working out.
أنا أتمرن
I've been waiting for you here
لقد كنت في انتظارك هنا
for a few days,
لبضعة أيام
but your parents say
لكن والديك يقولان
you're very busy these days.
أنت مشغول جدا هذه الأيام
So,
لذلك
have you been busy lately?
هل كنت مشغول في الآونة الأخيرة؟
I'm indeed busy these days.
أنا مشغول بالفعل هذه الأيام
So I can't see you.
لذلك لا يمكنني رؤيتك
Then you should go back and rest.
ثم يجب أن تعود وتستريح
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Prince Ying.
الأمير ينغ
Why did you come
لماذا جئت
to see me?
لرؤيتي؟
I recently found a little something
وجدت مؤخرا شيئا ما
I'd like to give you.
أود أن أعطيك
I think
أعتقد
you'll like it.
سوف يعجبك
This is rare.
هذا نادر
Do you really like it?
هل تحبها حقًا؟
Of course.
بالطبع
Is this for me?
هل هذه لي؟
I didn't expect you to love
لم أكن أتوقع منك أن تحبي
this ugly thing.
هذا الشيء القبيح
Since it's ugly, why did you buy it?
نظرا لأنه قبيح، لماذا اشتريته؟
No.
لا
Why are you angry again?
لماذا أنت غاضبة مرة أخرى؟
I was trying
كنت أحاول
to make you happy.
أن تسعدوا
Are you trying to make me happy?
هل تحاول أن تجعلني سعيدة؟
Why?
لماذا؟
Because
لأنك
when you're not happy,
عندما لا تكون سعيدًا
I can't see you.
لا أراك
When I can't see you,
عندما لا أراك
I'm unhappy as well.
أنا تعيسة أيضا
So
لذلك
what do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
I think
أعتقد
that's what it means.
هذا ما يعنيه
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
For you.
نيابة عنك
Why are you so preoccupied?
لماذا أنت مشغول جدا؟
After ten years
بعد عشر سنوات
of trusting you,
من الثقة بك
I didn't expect you
لم أكن أتوقع منك
to be someone of the enemy.
أن تكون شخصا من العدو
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
I am not with the enemy.
أنا لست مع العدو
I am with you.
أنا معك
I'm not talking about you.
أنا لا أتحدث عنك
Of course you are,
بالطبع أنت لست كذلك
but he is.
لكنه كذلك
So what are you going to do?
ماذا ستفعلين إذًا؟
He did not simply betray,
لم يخون ببساطة
I believe
أعتقد
he actually faltered.
في الحقيقة
there is a reason
هناك سبب
why you chose to trust him
لماذا اخترت أن تثق به
ten years ago.
قبل عشر سنوات
Now that he's faltering,
الآن بعد أن تعثر
you should win him back
يجب أن تفوز به في العودة
and make him
اجعله
loyal to you completely.
مخلص لك تماما
I get it.
فهمت
Thank you, Liuli.
شكرًا لك يا ليولي
Why did you indict me again?
لماذا دعوته لي مجددًا؟
It's just a drink.
إنه مجرد مشروب
Why did you indict me?
لماذا دعوتني؟
I have no one else to indict.
ليس لدي أحد آخر للدعوة
You went to brothel.
إنه نبيذ الزهري
- Brothel? - Beat him
- نبيذ فلوريل؟ - اضربيه
so I can indict you as well tomorrow.
حتى أتمكن من الانضمام غدا
I...
أنا...
No violence.
لا عنف
Stop fooling around.
توقف عن المزاح
Prince Consort.
الأمير القرين
I cannot agree with
لا أستطيع أن أتفق مع
(Prince Consort, Xie Linzhou) what you have just said.
(الأمير القرين، شي ليتشو) ما قلته للتو
We are all Grand Preceptor Du's students.
نحن جميعا طلاب المعلم الكبير دو
Do you still remember his advice?
هل ما زلت تتذكر نصيحته؟
An official
مسؤول
should take into account
ينبغي أن يأخذ في الاعتبار
the importance of the people and the State.
أهمية و الدولة
But today you are caught up in
ولكن اليوم أنت محاصر
your personal and trivial matter.
شؤونك الشخصية التافهة
What a disgrace.
يا لها من خيانة
You are right.
أنت على حق
Yes.
نعم
- Please forgive us. - Yes.
- أرجوك سامحنا - نعم
We're indebted to his teaching.
نحن مدينون له
Yes.
نعم
I was out of line.
كنت خارج حدودي
I hope you all will forgive me.
آمل أن تغفر لي جميعًا
- No. - You don't have to.
- لا - لا داعي لذلك
I've just returned to the capital today
عدت إلى العاصمة اليوم فقط
and I'm going to report to His Majesty.
وسأبلغ جلالة الإمبراطور
I'll see you all next time.
سأراك طوال المرة القادمة
Take care, Prince Consort.
اعتني بنفسك يا أمير القرين
- See you again. - Goodbye.
- أراك لاحقا - وداعًا
It's been a long time since I've seen him.
مضى وقت طويل منذ أن رأيته
Prince Consort Xie
الأمير القرين شي
is becoming more like the Grand Preceptor.
أصبحت أشبه المعلم الكبير
His term as the Governor of Jin
ولايته كحاكم لجين
has ended.
انتهت
He is returning to report on his duties.
سيعود للإبلاغ عن مهامه
I wonder if he will
أتساءل عما إذا كان سيفعل
stay in the capital.
سيبقى في العاصمة
Prince.
الأمير
Qing Yue is dead.
تشينغ يويه مات
I think the Crown Prince
أعتقد أن ولي عهد
sent someone to kill him.
أرسل شخصا لقتله
I didn't expect them
لم أكن أتوقع منهم
to discover the trail so quickly.
اكتشاف الدليل بسرعة كبيرة
We have to move again.
علينا أن نتحرك مجددًا
Grandfather.
الأجد
Drink this medicine first.
اشربي هذا الدواء أولًا
You can continue later.
يمكنك الاستمرار لاحقا
The subject of this test
موضوع هذا الاختبار
is more important than my life.
أهم من حياتي
Just put it aside.
فقط ضعه جانبا
I'll drink after I'm done.
سأشرب بعد انتهائي من الطعام
Grandfather.
جدي
Why don't you take a break?
لم لا تأخذين قسطا من الراحة؟
Let me write it for you.
دعني أكتب لك
Grandfather.
الأجد
I'm old.
أنا كبير في السن
I don't know if I can last
لا أعرف إن كنت أستطيع الاستمرار
until the envoy meeting.
حتى اجتماع المبعوث
I also don't know
أنا لا أعرف أيضا
if I can hold out until you get married.
ما إذا كان بإمكاني الاستمرار حتى تتزوج
Xiuying,
شي يينغ
you're like me.
أنت مثلي
I am concerned about you.
أنا قلق بشأنك
Grandfather.
الأجد
Grand Preceptor.
المعلم الكبير
Prince Consort Xie is back in the capital.
الأمير القرين شي عادت إلى العاصمة
He's here to see you.
إنه هنا لرؤيتك
Grandfather.
جد
Master.
معلمي
I'm sorry
أنا آسف
I couldn't visit you earlier.
لم أستطع زيارتك في وقت سابق
Here.
هنا
Slowly.
ببطء
You were busy in Jin Ridge.
كنت مشغول في جين ريدج
It's not like
الأمر ليس هكذا
you didn't visit me on purpose.
لم تزورني عن قصد
Please rise.
انهض أرجوك
How are you doing?
كيف حالك؟
I'm glad to see you.
أنا سعيد لرؤيتك
Grandfather.
جد
(Blossoming Flowers)
(أزهار مزدهرة)
Who sent so many
الذي أرسل الكثير
foolish books?
الكتب الحمقاء؟
They were from Princess Jiamin.
كانوا من الأميرة جيامين
She also told me
قالت لي أيضا
to make sure you read them.
للتأكد من قراءتها
If you can't stand it,
إذا كنت لا تستطيع تحمل ذلك
I can tell you about it.
يمكنني أن أخبرك به
Then all the more reason for me to refuse.
إذن سبب رفضني
Miss.
الآنسة
I know
أعرف
you love reading story books.
تحب قراءة كتب القصص
Come on, read it.
هيا، قرأه
Blossoming Flowers.
أزهار مزدهرة
What is this about?
ما الأمر؟
The book is about
عن القصة
a princess consort who dies of illness.
قرينة أميرة تموت من المرض
The prince marries her little sister
الأمير يتزوج أختها الصغيرة
because she has a resemblance
لأن لديها شبها
to her.
لها
Yes.
نعم
Flowers in the Shadow.
الزهور في الظل
This book is about
هذا الكتاب عن
a scholar
باحث
who made a demon
الذي صنع شيطان
take the form of his dead wife
في شكل زوجته الموتى
to repay his kindness.
لرد لطفته
Jiamin.
جيامين
What is she trying to convey?
ما الذي تحاول نقله؟
She's trying to say...
إنها تحاول أن تقول
What she's trying to say is that
ما تحاول قوله هو
everyone in the capital knows
الجميع في العاصمة يعرفون
that the second daughter
أن الإبنة الثانية
of Princess Le Yang
للأميرة لي يانغ
is coming to the capital.
قادم إلى العاصمة
So be careful
لذلك كن حذرا
not to be taken as a substitute.
ألا تؤخذ كبديل
So ridiculous.
سخيفة جدا
Let's go.
لنذهب
Let's ask around.
لنسأل في كل مكان
Take care, Miss.
اعتني بنفسك يا آنسة
What?
ماذا؟
I've got news for you.
لدي أخبار لك
You must
يجب عليك
never tell anyone.
لا تخبر أحدًا أبدا
Tell me.
أخبرني
I'm a very tight-lipped person.
أنا شخص ثقيل جدا
Princess Le Yang
الأميرة لي يانغ
is coming to the capital
قادم إلى العاصمة
with her second daughter, Xie Yao.
مع ابنتها الثانية، شي ياو
What?
ماذا؟
The envoy meeting is about to take place.
إن اجتماع المبعوث هو على وشك أن يتم
They are coming to see it.
إنهم قادرون على رؤيته
That's not it.
ليس الأمر كذلك
They are coming here this time
إنهما قادمان إلى هنا هذه المرة
to marry Xie Yao to the Crown Prince.
للزواج من شيه ياو إلى ولي عهد
Princess Hua, listen.
الأميرة هوا، استمعي
What?
ماذا؟
Xie Yao is going to marry the Crown Prince.
شيه ياو سوف يذهب تزوج ولي عهد
Princess Le Yang and Prince Consort Xie's
الأميرة لي يانغ والأمير القرين شي
eldest daughter
البنت الأكبر
was a well-educated
كانت متعلمة جيدا
and virtuous lady.
و
It's a pity that she died so young,
من المؤسف أنها ماتت صغيرا جدا
but their second daughter isn't bad either.
لكن ابنتهما الثانية ابنتهما ليست سيئة أيضًا
- Yes. - If she were to marry His Highness,
- نعم - إذا كانت ستتزوج من الأمير
wouldn't it be...
ألا يكون...
a shame?
من العار؟
(Xie Yao.)
(شي ياو)
Who is she to steal His Highness from me?
من هي لسرقة سموه مني؟
Why?
لماذا؟
- His Highness is so popular.
- الأمير محبوب جدًا
(Pretentious Hour)
(لحظة التظاهر)
Prince.
أمير
What do you think?
ما رأيك
It's a nice place, isn't it?
إنه مكان جميل، أليس كذلك؟
Come here.
اقترب
Closer.
أقرب
A little closer.
أقرب قليلا
Can't you
ألا يمكنك
find somewhere better?
العثور على مكان أفضل؟
Prince.
أيها الأمير
We have searched many places.
لقد بحثنا عن أماكن عديدة
If we don't want to be discovered,
إذا لم نرغب في اكتشافنا
we need to keep a low profile.
نحن بحاجة إلى الاحتفاظ بمكانة ضعيفة
If God wants to give a man a great task,
إذا أراد الله أن أعطى الرجل مهمة عظيمة
he must first suffer his heart and mind
يجب أن يعاني أولا من قلبه وفكره
and work his muscles and bones.
ويعمل عضلاته وعظامه
I, Jiang Sha, can accept this place.
أنا، جيانغ شا، يمكنني أن أقبل هذا المكان
Great.
عظيم
Then stay here.
إذن ابقي هنا
On second thoughts,
بالأفكار الثانية
I can't.
لا أستطيع
I can't count on others.
لا يمكنني الاعتماد على الآخرين
I have to do it myself.
يجب أن أفعل ذلك
♪A new song is played by my fingers♪
♪ أغنية جديدة يعزف بها أصابعي ♪
♪I can't talk or sleep under the moon♪
♪ لا أستطيع التحدث أو النوم تحت القمر ♪
♪I'm missing someone walking around the pavilion♪
♪ أفتقد شخصا ما أتجول حول الجناح ♪
♪I can hardly tell anyone♪
♪ لا أستطيع أن أقول لأي شخص ♪
♪Who will be in this mortal♪
♪ من سيكون في هذه الوفاة ♪
♪Know my heart and how I cry without showing anyone♪
♪ عرفت قلبي وأنت كيف أبكي دون إظهار أي شخص ♪
♪The memory has gone♪
♪ لقد اختفت الذاكرة ♪
♪Whose face is showing in my dream♪
♪ يظهر وجهي في حلمي ♪
♪How many times do I need to go through this♪
♪ كم مرة أحتاج إلى المرور بهذا ♪
♪Crying alone in front of the window♪
♪ الزواج وحده أمام النافذة ♪
♪Hearing the rain last night♪
♪ الاستماع إلى المطر ليلة أمس ♪
♪But my heart will not change♪
♪ لكن قلبي لن يتغير ♪
♪The clouds are being covered by the shadow of the moon♪
♪ الغيوم يتم تغطيتها في ظل القمر ♪
♪Who is rolling up the sleeve with the wind♪
♪ من يدمر النوم بالرياح ♪
♪Not worried about the grudges but for the ones not around♪
♪ لا تقلق بشأن الضغينة ولكن من لا حولها ♪
♪Telling my sorrowfulness in Fengyi Pavilion♪
♪ عزيمة في جناح فنغ يي ♪
♪But it's a shame a few autumns have passed♪
♪ لكنه من المؤسف لقد مرت بعض الأوهام ♪
♪It's hard to balance between the world and the one we love♪
♪ من الصعب التوازن بين العالم بين العالم الذي نحب ♪
♪The clouds are being covered by the shadow of the moon♪
♪ الغيوم يتم تغطيتها في ظل القمر ♪
♪I'm waiting while turning back♪
♪ أنا أنتظر بينما أعود ♪
♪I sighed as the old days are no longer here anymore♪
♪ شاهدت كالأيام الخوالي لم يعد هنا بعد الآن ♪
♪How many worries are there♪
♪ كم عدد الهموم هناك ♪
♪How many of us can grow old together♪
♪ كم الكثير منا يمكن أن يكبر في السن معا ♪
♪I wish you can have the world and the one you love♪
♪ أتمنى أن يكون لديك العالم العالم الذي تحبينه ♪